DANIEL MARQUES

Gameplay Programmer | Informatics and Computing Engineer

PERSONAL

- Porto, Portugal
- ▼ danfil.marques@gmail.com
- github.com/rendoir
- rendoir.github.io

PROFILE

Experienced gameplay programmer passionate about creating masterpiece games and providing memorable gaming experiences.

My goal in life is to be a part of developing games that are appreciated as works of art. Games that live on in players' minds years after playing them. Games that perfectly balance a compelling narrative, engaging mechanics and immersive environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Gameplay Programmer

Ubisoft Québec

January 2022 - Present

At Ubisoft Québec, I worked on Assassin's Creed Shadows for the entire production phase and during post-launch.

I was responsible for the technical implementation of various new gameplay systems. Namely, the Opportunity, Scouting and Ally systems. For each system and its multiple ever-evolving features, I conceptualised the code architecture, envisioned the data setup, and implemented the code. This was accomplished by working closely with colleagues from different disciplines and teams, namely game designers, technical designers, quest designers, testers, and other programmers. Besides code ownership of the new systems, I was responsible for others, such as the exploration system, and I contributed to online collectables, the hideout, notoriety, achievements, and more.

Throughout the project, I applied my leadership skills to elevate the team by providing meaningful insights when discussing code architecture, by fostering their knowledge of C++, memory and performance, and by promoting high standards on our codebase through code reviews and discussions.

Junior Gameplay Programmer

Ubisoft Berlin

August 2020 - January 2022

At Ubisoft Berlin, I worked on Far Cry 6 on the gameplay team. The game was at its closing stage when I joined and, consequently, my work on this project mainly consisted of fixing bugs and crashes and polishing features spanning the areas of gameplay ingredients, gameplay systems, game mode logic, physics, weapons and gadgets, vehicles, 3Cs (character, camera, controls), network replication, quest scripting, and more.

I learned a lot during this time simply by virtue of being exposed to a large codebase and working with very knowledgeable people. Amongst the various self-improvements resulting from working at Ubisoft Berlin, I'd highlight my debugging skills, the ability to understand and navigate large codebases, my understanding of common implementations of some game systems, and teamwork and communication skills.

EDUCATION

Integrated Master's Degree in Informatics and Computing Engineering Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto

2015 - 2020

Throughout this bachelor and master's degree, I studied mathematics, computer architecture, algorithms and data structures, computer graphics, object-oriented programming, software engineering, artificial intelligence, parallel computing, game development, virtual and augmented reality and much more. During this time, I also autonomously deepened my knowledge of C++ and game development.